(+51) 943-440-048 Lima, Peru alejandro.latorre@pucp.edu.pe

Alejandro Latorre

Data Scientist / Data Analyst

medium@alejlatorre github.com/alejlatorre linkedin.com/in/alejandro-latorre-rojas

Bachelor of Sciences in Industrial Engineering at Pontifical University Catholic of Peru. Experienced and interested in Data Science & Analytics with emphasis on business applications (Pricing, Marketing, Product & Operations). Natural problem-solver, highly responsible and goal-oriented. Passionate about knowledge discovery from data to solve business problems while keeping the trade-off between quality and speed.

SKILLS

Tools and Languages Amazon QuickSight, AWS Lambda, BigQuery, Cloudera HUE (Hive + Impala), C#, Data Studio, Git,

Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Integration Services (SSIS), Kepler.gl, LaTeX, Looker, Python,

PowerBI, PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server and R.

Communication English (B2), French (lecture) and Portuguese (lecture).

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist @ AUNA

Retail Pharmacy Department

Dec, 2021 — Present

- Saved over S/36k per month after the execution of a proposal of warehouses redistribution and a coverage optimization using geoanalysis with Python and Kepler.gl.
- Developed a customer segmentation model and deployed an automated pipeline (integration of Python, AWS Lambda and GitHub Actions with Serverless framework).
- Designed and analyzed multiple AB tests for product features and marketing strategies.
- Developed a transactional forecast model for budgeting.
- Developed an association rules model for designing promotional strategies.
- Automated processes with Python and AWS Lambda for monitoring and measuring the impact of changes in delivery pricing.
- Responsible for the development of data-driven strategies across multiple business areas (operations, marketing and product).

Data Analyst SSr @ PedidosYa (Delivery Hero)

Sep, 2021 — Dec, 2021

Logistics & Operations Department

- Responsible for the analysis of performance of operations in the southern cities of Peru.
- Responsible for the demand forecast monitoring to improve the operational efficiency.
- · Responsible for the expansion opportunity assessment using geoanalysis techniques with Python and Kepler.gl.
- Responsible for monitoring the coverage optimization algorithm.

Business Intelligence Analyst @ PedidosYa (Delivery Hero)

Marketing & Strategy Department

May, 2021 — Sep, 2021

- Responsible for the analysis and development of strategies in the main business vertical (83% of its monthly revenue), which had a continuous growth of 7% per month.
- Responsible for designing, developing, deploying and automating multiple dashboards using DataStudio and BigQuery for daily, weekly and monthly business reviews.

Pricing Analytics Intern @ Banco de Crédito del Perú

Pricing & Analytics Department

Jan, 2021 — May, 2021

- Part of the team that developed the FX project (foreign exchange market) for the prediction of customer's closing quotation price.
- Developed a customer segmentation analysis using classification trees for financial products portfolio management.

Lending Strategy Intern @ Interbank

Jan, 2020 — Dec, 2020

Commercial Banking Department

- Designed and developed a desktop application in C# for the management of special commissions for corporate customers.
- Responsible for automation of data extraction, transformation and loading (ETL) processes with SQL Server Integration Services.
- Responsible for market analysis of financial products and services (Foreign Trade and Financing Sales).

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Data Science Tutor @ Coderhouse

Jul, 2022 — Present

Teaching Assistant in Data Analytics 1 & 2 @ Pontifical University Catholic of Peru

Mar, 2022 — Present

- Topics in Analytics 1: Data processing, exploratory data analysis, dimensionality reduction.
- Topics in Analytics 2: Regression models, segmentation, classification trees, clustering and association rules.

Teaching Assistant in Statistics for Engineering @ Pontifical University Catholic of Peru

Aug, 2019 — Dec, 2019

• Topics: Descriptive data analysis, basic applications of statistical inference and probabilities.

EDUCATION	
Bachelor of Sciences in Industrial Engineering, Pontifical University Catholic of Peru	2016 — 2021
Topics: Statistics, Operations Research, Systems Analysis and Design, Simulation and Data Mining	
Business Intelligence Specialization, Data Mining Consulting	2019
Topics: Database Management, Exploratory Data Analysis, ETL Implementation and Machine Learning	
CERTIFICATIONS	
Data Analyst with SQL certification, DataCamp	2020
Specialization course of Corporate Finances, Peruvian University of Applied Sciences	2020
Advanced Excel certification, Pontifical University Catholic of Peru	2019
Advanced SQL Server certification, Pontifical University Catholic of Peru	2019
First Certificate in English (B2), Cambridge University	2019
Python certification, Pontifical University Catholic of Peru	2019
ACTIVITIES	
Active writer in blogging platforms: Medium and Substack.	2022
Winner of a partial scholarship for "Contemporary Topics in Business Strategy" course in Pearson College London.	2020
Former member of Science & Engineering Faculty Council at PUCP.	2019 - 2020
Former member of athletics and rugby team at PUCP.	2016 - 2018
5 ,	